# PADDY YOOSIN

Toronto, ON M5V 1A3 ● (437)994-3785 ● paddykiprop@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

I am a highly motivated and skilled Flutter Developer with extensive experience in developing and maintaining mobile applications for various industries. With a positive "I can do it" attitude and a commitment to delivering high-quality results, I approach challenges enthusiastically and believe that "everything is possible". While working with a team, I possess excellent communication and interpersonal skills, which have enabled me to perform tasks, provide feedback, and manage time effectively. With a passion for innovation and a track record of meeting deadlines, I am confident in my reliability and ability to drive success and exceed expectations.

#### Skills

- Cross Platform Mobile Development:
   Experience in Flutter programming language;
   Dart Platform, DevTools, Flutter widgets, State management, Stateless widgets, Stateful widgets
- Native Mobile: Android development: Java programming language, Groovy, Kotlin Programming language, Android SDK, Dagger, performance, optimization and Coroutines iOS: Swift
- API and RESTful Service Development:
   Laravel (PHP) Framework, Pure PHP, Spring
   boot, JSON, GSON, Angular Framework and
   Node Js
- Design Patterns: Solid principals, MVVM
- Cloud Services: Google cloud functions, AWS, E2C, S3, RDS
- Automation and Version Control: GitHub,
   Bitbucket, Gitlab

- IDEs, Testing and Debugging: I used tools such as ADB (Android debug bridge), Dart analyzer, JUnit and IntelliJ IDEs, Android Studio, IntelliJ idea, Visual Studio and Visual Studio code
- Front-end Development: Flutter, React.js,
   Vue.js, HTML/CSS/JS, Android XML, Material
   design patterns and Bootstrap
- Backend Development, Database & Microservices: Java, Spring Boot, Node.js, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebase, PHP, Laravel, EC2, Sqlite, other relational databases
- Scripting Languages: PHP, python, Groovy, Javascript, Typescript, C#
- Other: Raspberry Pi, Arduino, testing, technical documentation and technical writing, code obfuscation and other encryption techniques

# Work History

Software Developer, 01/2023 to Current

SmartLobby - London

Worked on two projects:

# **Abobos Digital Signage:**

- Developed **Android TV** application for **signage**, ad and display automation.
- I contributed in **improving** the **compatibility** of the application from **50% to 95%** of the devices. I upgraded the app to be compatible with android 10, 11 and 12.
- I also rewrote code to ensure **synchronization** between server ad changes and live TV streaming **without interrupting** current ad display schedule
- Technologies and skills involved include; Java, Kotlin, Spring Boot, Flutter, Dart, Bitbucket, Github, Unit Tests, SQL, MySQL, Agile development.

#### PlanetVCF:

- Worked on PlanetVCF application API, Contact backup management application. Improved the
  performance of the mobile application by developing a mobile version of their website and PHP
  middleware to connect with the WordPress database for the PlanetVCF application.
- The **performance enhancement** achieved a significant **20***x* **speed improvement** on the application.
- Technologies used: Flutter, Kotlin, PHP, WordPress, MySQL, and GitHub.

#### **Android Developer**, 01/2022 to 08/2023

**Global Company for Engineering and Development (https://gecdoman.com/)** – Remote, Oman I worked on maintaining and adding features to a cab booking system with GPS, navigation and location system.

My tasks were

- Developing rest API using Node Js, Git, Postman, MySQL
- Fixing bugs and resubmitting applications to Apple and Play stores.
- Add new features to the application using Java, Kotlin, Node Js, and Angular technologies
- Support application deployment to new Geolocation
- Maintain AWS servers and fix any arising issues
- Rewrite algorithms to reduce the cost of Geolocation related services by 80%
- I pioneered new Emerging technologies and integrated to existing systems

The apps I help maintain are deployed in https://play.google.com/store

/apps/details?id=com.gaita.user&gl=US and

id1572271279/غايته-/id1572271279

# Lead Mobile Developer, 07/2018 to 12/2021

Trichain Technologies (https://trichaintechnologies.com) – Murang'a, Kenya

• The tasks involved in **managing projects**, delegating duties, and overseeing project management, with a strong emphasis on mobile app development.

- Successfully delivered over 20 projects, comprising mobile apps for both iOS and Android,
  highlighting a significant impact on project completion. My contribution increased confidence
  rating on Trichain by 3 points according to the company rating standards
- Utilized a diverse range of technologies, including **Flutter**, **Java**, **Kotlin**, Spring Boot, Linux, Git, Bitbucket, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, SQL, BLE, Bluetooth Beacons and Python, showcasing a broad skill set.
- Developed in-depth knowledge of the Android SDK, performance optimization, and the
  utilization of various tools and concepts such as AsyncTasks, Adapters, Fragments, OkHttp and
  Activities. Also demonstrated proficiency in design patterns, user interface design, usability, and
  post-launch product support.
- In addition to technical skills, a strong development of management skills, including prioritization, goal orientation, **problem-solving**, **scrum**, and **collaboration**, contributing to effectiveness in project management and team coordination.

# **Education**

**Bachelor of Science**: Software Engineering, 12/2020 **Muranga University of Technology** - Murang'a Kenya

### **Portfolio**

- Abobos Digital Signage <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.abobos.signage.player.app">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.abobos.signage.player.app</a>
- Ghaytah Cab App. <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gaita.user">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gaita.user</a>
- Celebrity Kenya <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fanswish">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fanswish</a>
- PlanetVCF <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.planetvcf.app">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.planetvcf.app</a>
- Double Dip Solutions Android <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.doubledipsolutions.double\_dip">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.doubledipsolutions.double\_dip</a>
- Double Dip Solutions Ios <a href="https://apps.apple.com/sa/app/double-dip-solutions/id1578804344">https://apps.apple.com/sa/app/double-dip-solutions/id1578804344</a>
- Ahil Nnu (Educational Game) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yoosin.ahilnnu
- Amawal Dictionnaire <a href="https://play.google.com/store">https://play.google.com/store</a>
   /apps/details?id=com.geekycorp.TifnaghDictionary
- Amawal Qamous (قاموس) <a href="https://play.google.com/store">https://play.google.com/store</a>
   /apps/details?id=com.yoosin.TifnaghDictionaryArabic
- Loving Hands Hygiene Health & Wellness <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=apps.trichain.hairdresser">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=apps.trichain.hairdresser</a>